Guide to the League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area records, 1948-2009
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area records
1948-2009
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives
League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area
C0031
35.25 linear feet (71 boxes)
The League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area Records contains materials from the LWVFA's activities from 1948-2009, including studies, information on political issues, meeting minutes, newsletters, correspondence, and photographs.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by the League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area between 1995 and 2009.
Accruals
Further accruals are expected.
Historical Information
The League of Women Voters (LWV) was founded in 1920 by Carrie Chapman Catt, a leader in the women's suffragist movement. Its purpose is to encourage citizens to participate actively in government by supporting the party of their choice. While the LWV is a nonpartisan organization, and therefore does not support individual candidates, it does take a position on issues of a national, state, and local scale selected by the membership. Such issues of the past included support for a minimum wage, child labor laws, and equal opportunity for women in government.
In Virginia, the LWV began as the Equal Suffrage League, which worked diligently for the ratification of the nineteenth amendment. The Equal Suffrage League joined the national LWV and created a state league. The first local league in Virginia was established in Richmond, followed by chapters in Alexandria and Arlington.
The League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area (LWVFA) was granted full league status in 1948. However, the LWVFA of the present day was established in 1964 after the town of Fairfax became a city in 1961 and thus a separate governmental jurisdiction from the County of Fairfax.
Scope and Content
The League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area Records contains material from the LWVFA's activities from 1955-2008, including studies, information on political issues, meeting minutes, newsletters, correspondence, and photographs. The collection is organized in 9 series for easy use and research. The 9 series are: Board Meetings and Minutes, Programs, Publications, Correspondence, Conventions and Meetings, Subject Files, Oral History, Photographs, and Oversized.
The first series, Board Meetings and Minutes, contains the board meetings and minutes of the League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area. The documents detail the discussions and planning of the League Board. The series is arranged chronologically and details the activities of the League at their meetings.
The second series, Programs, contains documents pertaining to the programs and activities sponsored by the League, including local, national, and international issues. In addition to voting programs, the League engaged in a variety of other programs, including land use, education, and criminal justice.
The third series, Publications, contains the various publications of the League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area. Most notably, this series includes the chapter's newsletter, the "Bulletin." Additionally, the series includes other publications by the League, including recycling and voting guides.
The fourth series, Correspondence, contains the letters and messages between the League and organizations such as the Virginia Senate and House of Delegates, the U.S. Congress, and the office of the Governor of Virginia. The series also contains letters between members of the league regarding various activities of the LWVFA.
The fifth series, Conventions and Meetings, contains information about the annual meetings of the LWVFA. The series also contains workbooks and pamphlets about the Virginia and National Conventions for the League of Women Voters.
The sixth series, Subject Files, contains information concerning the miscellaneous activities of the LWVFA, such as schools, environmental policy, finances, construction site safety, and historic preservation.
The seventh series, Oral History, includes transcripts and audio recordings of LWVFA members, such as Lean Packard and Martha Pennino.
The eighth series, Photographs, contains photographs of LWVFA members and important events.
The ninth series, Electronic Records, contains electronic records in ASCII format on 3.5 inch and 5.25 inch floppy discs. The records accompany the 1994 Election voters guides and candidate questionaires.
The tenth series, Oversize, contains materials such as signs, scrapbooks, and memorabilia.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in 10 series:
Series 1: Board Meetings and Minutes, 1955-1994 (Boxes 1-8)
Series 2: Programs, 1962-1999 (Boxes 8-17)
Series 3: Publications, 1953-2009 (Boxes 17-30, 71)
Series 4: Correspondence, 1972-1998 (Boxes 30-31)
Series 5: Conventions and Meetings, 1965-2008 (Boxes 32-34)
Series 6: Subject Files, 1953-2006 (Boxes 34-63)
Series 7: Oral History, 1995-1996 (Boxes 63-65)
Series 8: Photographs, 2002 (Box 65)
Series 9: Electronic Records, 1994 (Box 65)
Series 10: Oversize, 1964-1980s (Boxes 66-70)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
The George Mason University Special Collections and Archives also holds other collections for research on the political life of women in Northern Virginia such as the, the, and the.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area
Geographical Names:
Fairfax (Va.)--Politics and government
Subjects:
Citizens' associations--Virginia--Fairfax; Political participation--Virginia--Fairfax
Contents List
- Series 1: Board Meetings and Minutes, 1955-1994; (7.5 boxes)
  Series 1 contains the board meetings and minutes of the League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area. The series is arranged chronologically and details the activities of the League at their meetings. Series 1 is contained in 6.5 boxes.
  - Board Minutes, Jan. 1955-Dec. 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board Minutes, Jan. 1958-Dec. 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board Minutes, Jan. 1962-Dec. 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board Minutes, Jan. 1964-Dec. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board Minutes, Jan. 1966-Dec. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board Minutes, Jan. 1967-Dec. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board Minutes, Feb. 1969-March 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board Minutes, April 1970-Dec. 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Board Minutes, Jan. 1972-Dec. 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Board Minutes, Jan. 1973- Jan. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Board Minutes, Jan. 1974-Dec. 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Board Minutes, Jan. 1978-Dec. 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Annual Meeting Kits, 1957-1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Annual Meeting Kits, 1957-1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Board Meetings, Jan. 1982-Dec. 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes and Agenda, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Minutes and Agenda, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes and Agenda, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Memo to the Board, June 3, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Minutes and Agenda, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Board Minutes and Addenda, Jan.-Dec. 1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Board Minutes and Addenda, Jan.-Dec. 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Board Minutes and Addenda, Jan.-Dec. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - LWVFA Board Minutes and Add., Jan.- Dec. 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes/Agenda, July 1987-June 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Minutes/Agenda, July 1987-June 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Minutes/Agenda, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Board Minutes, Jan. 1989-June 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Board Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Board Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Board Minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Board Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Education Fund Meeting Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Board Summary: NCA, 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Board: President's Packet, 1988-1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - LWVUS Board Reports, 1996-1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - LWVFA Officers of Boards, 1962-1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - LWVFA Board Officers, 1950-1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Board: Policies, 1971 -1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Education Fund: Board Minutes, 1988-1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Board Testimony, Dec. 4 1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Programs Board and Commissions Annual Reports, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Board Memberlist, 1965-1998 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Membership: Directories, 1991-1999 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Board Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Education Fund Meeting Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Board Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Education Fund Meeting Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - LWVFA Post Board, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Board Minutes, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Education Fund Meeting Minutes, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Board Minutes, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Education Fund Meeting Minutes, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Board Minutes, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Board Meeting and Minutes, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Education Fund Meeting Minutes, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Board Meeting and Minutes, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Board Meeting and Minutes, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Education Fund Meeting Minutes, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Board Testimony, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - General Fund Meeting Minutes, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Series 2: Programs, 1962-1999; (9 boxes)
  Series 2 contains documents pertaining to the programs and activities sponsored by the League, including local, national, and international issues. The documents are contained in 9.5 boxes and are arranged chronologically.
  - United Nations, 1962-1985 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Voters Service Programs, 1963-2002 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Voting Rights-Redistricting, 1965-1981 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Reapportionment, 1965-1984 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Aid and Trade, 1967-1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Urban Problems, 1967-1978 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Land Use-Local, 1968-1981 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Housing, 1968-1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Political Parties, 1968-1984 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Water, 1968-1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Public Officials-BOS Swearing In, 1968-1992 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - System of Justice, 1969-1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Poverty, 1969-1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Transportation, 1969-1987 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Description NCA, 1969-1997 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Government Structure-Local and State, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Schools, 1970-1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - ERA, 1970-1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Congress, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Fiscal-Local, 1971-1981 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - State and Local Justice, 1971-1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Environmental, 1971-1990 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The League (Gen'l) Va Potpourri, 1972-1978 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - State Judicial System, 1972-1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Report From the Hill, 1972-1982 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Juvenile Justice, 1973-1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Equal Rights Amendment (ERA), 1973-1983 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Public Officials-State Legislative Reception, 1973-1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Land Use-National/State, 1974-1981 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Fairfax City, 1974-1981 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Housing, 1974-1983 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Unit Action, 1974-1984 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Elderly H.R., 1975 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The Presidency, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Energy, 1975-1981 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Energy, 1975-1981 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Government-Campaign Finance, Congress, Reapportionment, Presidency, DC Home Rule, Voting Rights Act, 1975-1983 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Action Taken Log (Chrono List), 1975-1987 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Public Officials-Local, 1975-1991 (Box 12, Box 8)
  - Action Guidelines, 1975-1994 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Public Officials-State Senate, 1975-1998 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Action Campaign-School Bonds, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Virginia-Fiscal, 1976-1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Women's Issues, 1976-1986 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Health, 1976-1986 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Water, 1976-1987 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Health and NCA, 1976-1988 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Boards and Commissions Guidelines for LWVFA Reps., 1976-1989 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Public Officials-BOS Chairman, 1976-1998 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Public Officials, 1976-1998 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Local Government, 1977-1981 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Election Laws, 1977-1982 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Justice/Juv. Justice, 1977-1983 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Women's Issues: Pay Equity, Divorce Laws, Inheritance, Homemaker's Rights, 1977-1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - International Relations, 1977-1985 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Fair Campaign Practices, 1977-1986 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Transportation, 1977-1987 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Bulletin Articles, 1977-1987 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Housing-Social Services, 1977-1987 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Fairfax Legislative Program, 1978-1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Environment-Air, 1978-1986 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - NCA Programs, 1978-1986 (Box 15, Folder 2 `)
  - Action Taken (Local Level), 1978-1987 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Schools, 1979-1986 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Development Consensus Reports, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Constitution, 1980-1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Report From the Hill, 1982-1983 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Transportation-HOV/I66, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - National Security/Nuclear War, 1983-1986 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Unit Action, 1984-1987 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Action Taken NCA Level, 1986-1996 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Description-National Impact on Issues, 1986-2000 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Action Taken-Local Level, 1987-1989 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Public Officials State Legislative Reception, 1989-1999 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Action Alerts National, 1990-1995 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Action Procedures, 1990-1997 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Action Taken-Action Chrono File, 1990-1997 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Action Taken-National Chrono File, 1992-2001 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Action Taken-Action Chrono File, 1993-1995 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Program Action, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Public Officials, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Public Officials-State Delegates/U.S. Senate, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Programs, 2001-2002 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Series 3: Publications, 1953-2009; (14 boxes)
  Series 3 contains the various publications of the League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area. Most notably, this series includes the chapter's newsletter, the "Bulletin." The series is arranged chronologically in 13 boxes.
  - Bulletin and Study, August 1953-October 1956 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Bulletin and Study, April 1957-March 1959 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Bulletin and Study, April 1959-March 1961 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Bulletin and Study, April 1961-March 1963 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Bulletin and Study, April 1963-May 1964 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Bulletin and Study, June 1964-December 1964 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Bulletin and Study, Jan. 1965-Dec. 1965 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Bulletin and Study, Jan. 1966-March 1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Bulletin and Study, April 1966-Aug. 1966 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Bulletin and Study, Sept. 1966-March 1967 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Bulletin and Study, April 1967-June 1967 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Bulletin and Study, Sept. 1967-March 1968 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Bulletin and Study, April 1968-March 1969 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Bulletin and Study, April 1969-Sept. 1969 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Bulletin and Study, Oct. 1969-March 1970 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Bulletin and Study, March 1970-Sept. 1970 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Bulletin and Study, Oct. 1970-Mar. 1971 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Bulletin and Study, April 1971-March 1972 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Bulletin and Study, April 1972-March 1973 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Bulletin and Study, April 1973-Oct. 1973 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Bulletin and Study, Nov. 1973-Jan. 1974 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Bulletin and Study, March 1974-Dec. 1974 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1975-Dec. 1975 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1976-Dec. 1976 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1977-Dec. 1977 (Box 21, Box 5)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1978-Dec. 1978 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1979-Dec. 1979 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1980-Dec. 1980 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1981-Dec. 1981 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1982-Dec. 1982 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1983-Dec. 1983 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1984-Dec. 1984 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1985-Dec. 1985 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - LWVFA Bulletin, Jan. 1986-Dec. 1986 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - LWVFA Bulletin, Jan. 1987-Dec. 1987 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - LWVFA Bulletin, Jan. 1988-Dec. 1988 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - LWVFA Bulletin, Jan. 1989-Dec. 1989 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - LWVFA Bulletin, Jan. 1990-Dec. 1990 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - LWVFA Bulletin, Jan. 1991-Dec. 1991 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - LWVFA Bulletin, Jan. 1992-Dec. 1992 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - LWVFA Bulletin, Jan. 1993-Dec. 1993 (Box 24, Box 4)
  - LWFVA Bulletin, Jan. 1994-Dec. 1994 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - LWVFA Bulletin, Jan. 1995-Dec. 1995 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - LWVFA Bulletin, Jan. 1996-Dec. 1996 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - LWVFA Bulletins, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Bulletin, Vol. 50, Nos. 5-10, Jan.-June 1998 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Bulletin, Sept. 1998-Sept. 1999 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Letters and Bulletins, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Letters and Bulletins, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Bulletin, Sept.-Dec. 2001 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - LWVFA Bulletin, 2003-2005 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Bulletin Vol. 56 No. 5, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Bulletin Vol. 56 No. 6, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Bulletin Vol. 56 No. 7, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Bulletin Vol. 56 No. 9, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Bulletin Vol. 56 No. 10, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Bulletin Vol. 58 No. 1, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Bulletin Vol. 59 No. 3, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Bulletin Vol. 59 No. 4, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Bulletin Vol. 58 No. 7, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Bulletin Vol. 59 No. 5-6, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Bulletin Vol. 59 No. 7, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Bulletin Vol. 59 No. 8, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Bulletin Vol. 59 No. 9, May 2007 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Bulletin, Sept. 2007 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Bulletin, April 2008 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Bulletin, September 2008-January 2009 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Member Handbook, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Handbooks, 1969-1990 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Publication Catalog and Bulletins, 1955-1986 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Publications, 1955 - 1987 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Action Local "Here We Stand", 1967-2001 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Who Makes The Decisions, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Facts For Voters Samples, 1970-1986 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Making It Work: a guide to training election workers, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Supercity/Hometown, U.S.A., 1974 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Facts For Voters, 1974-1976 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Publication: Distribution Subscription Service, 1975-1980 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Publication Production, 1975-1985 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - P.R. Press Release, 1976-1994 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Facts For Voters, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Facts For Voters, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Handbook for Local League Leaders, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - V.S. Info from LWVUS and LWVVA, 1978-1988 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Facts For Voters, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Calendars, 1981-1983 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Facts For Voters, 1981-1982 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - The Women's Vote: Beyond the Nineteenth Amendment, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Your Legal Right As A Woman: A Handbook for Virginians, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Voter Samples, 1984-1995 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Facts For Voters, 1983-1985 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Facts For Voters, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Fairfax County Goals Advisory Commission Final Report, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Report of the Citizen's Committeefor the Review of Land Use and Transportation Planning for Fairfax County, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Safety On Tap: A Citizen's Drinking Water Handbook, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Facts For Voters, 1987-1988 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - V.S. Info from LWVUS and LWVVA, 1988-1991 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Legislative Newsletter, 1988-1996 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Facts For Voters, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Understanding Economic Policy, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Publications Catalog, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Member Handbook and Bylaws, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Procedures Calendar, 1990-1995 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Handbooks, 1990-1995 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Fairfax County Report and Recommendations: County Revenues, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Facts For Voters, 1990-1991 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Facts For Voters, 1991-1994 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Community: Women's Center, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Your Virginia State Government and Other Publications, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Voters' Guide-General Election, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Voter Guides, 1994-2008 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Clearinghouse Database Survey, 1995 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Diamond Jubilee Anniversary, 1995 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Anniversary Workbook, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - School Board Election, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Virginia General Election, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Virginia General Election-Fairfax Co. Board of Supervisors, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Virginia General Election-Fairfax Co. Sheriff, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Virginia General Election-Fairfax Co. School Board, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Virginia General Election-Commonwealth Attorney, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Virginia General Election-General Assembly, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Here We Stand, Printer's Copy, 1996-1999 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - National Voter Magazine, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - "Your Virginia Government", 2001 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Women's Legacies, 2001 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Voting Seminar, 2001 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Electricity Deregulation Program, 2001-2002 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Publications, 2009 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    Facts for Voters; Fairfax Voter (Vol. 61, Issue 7-10)
  - Fairfax Voter, 2009-2010 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    Volume 62
  - Fairfax Voter, 2010-2011 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    Volume 63
  - Facts for Voters, 2011 (Box 71, Folder 3)
- Series 4: Correspondence, 1972-1998; (1.5 boxes)
  Series 4 contains the correspondence among League members and between the League and various other agencies, most notably members of the Virginia State Senate and House of Delegates, as well as members of the U.S. Congress. The series is arranged chronologically in 2 boxes.
  - Correspondence and Testimony, 1972-1996 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Va. Senate and House of Reps., 1973-1989 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - P.R. Media Relations Letter to the Editor, 1974-1991 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: U.S. Congress, 1975-1984 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Communications: Incoming, 1976-1995 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Voters' Service: Correspondence, 1976-1996 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1983 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Annual: Reports to National, 1978-1981 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports: To National, 1979-1984 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Form Letters, 1984-1997 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Program Action: U.S. Senators, 1985-1998 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Internal, 1986-1995 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Recycling Guide: Solicitation Letters and Responses, 1989-1991 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Recycling Guides-Letters from Community (Govt. Offices and Individuals), 1990-1991 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Communitcations: Outgoing, 1992-1995 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - League Correspondence, 1999-2003 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 15)
- Series 5: Conventions and Meetings, 1965-2008; (2.5 boxes)